

Contact Details

Pablo Ibieta

CPF 236.705.918-40

Mibieta.pablo@gmail.com

pibieta@if.usp.br

☐ (+55) 11 959 410 565

Work Address

Alameda Vicente Pinzon Nr. 51, 13th floor. CEP 04547-130 São Paulo, Brazil.

Personal Address

Rua Francisco Isoldi 226 Apto 64B CEP 05441-040 São Paulo, Brazil.

Details and Publications

Curriculo Lattes
https://bit.ly/2CXGU8i
in/in/pibieta

?pibieta

Languages

Spanish: Mother tongue English: Advanced Portuguese: Fluent

J. Pablo Ibieta-Jimenez

Physicist - Data Scientist

About me Since 2012, I have worked as a scientific researcher in the area of Quantum Physics. During this period, I have acquired advanced mathematical knowledge and learned several computational skills concerning data analysis. This involves the manipulation and interpretation of data and the use of statistical tools to compare data to models. I currently work as a Data Scientist focused in building credit risk models and delivering them as robust services, using state-of-the-art techniques and technologies.

Experience

Aug 2019 - Present

Data Scientist, Serasa Experian DataLab, São Paulo, Brazil. Activities Include:

- Processing large amounts of data to build Machine Learning based credit risk models.
- Delivering the models as robust APIs for user consumption.
- Daily basis interaction with both clients and stakeholders.

Sep 2012 - Sep 2019

Researcher and Teaching Assistant, Instituto de Física, Universidade de São Paulo (USP). São Paulo, Brazil. Research projects include:

- Topological phases of matter, quantum physics and mathematical physics.
- Computer vision for astrophysical image classification.
- NLP and Deep Learning for conversational ChatBots.

Sep 2005 - Feb 2010

Junior Researcher and Teaching Assistant. Institute for Theoretical Physics, UMSA, Physics Department. La Paz, Bolivia.

Education

2015 - 2019

Ph. D. in Physics, Universidade de São Paulo (USP). São Paulo, Brazil.

2012 - 2015

M. Sc. in Physics, Universidade de São Paulo (USP) São Paulo, Brazil.

2004 - 2010

Bachelor in Physics, Universidad Mayor de San Andrés (UMSA). La Paz, Bolivia.

Skills

Technical

Machine Learning, Neural Networks, Simulations, Feature Engineering, Data Analysis, Visualization, Web.

Software Development

Python, R, C, C++, Mathematica, SQL, NoSQL, HTML, CSS.

Numpy, Pandas, seaborn, matplotlib, openCV, nltk, spacy, Flask, Django, Tensorflow, Keras, sklearn and XGBoost.